♪ ♪
Do you want subtitles for any video?
-=[ ai.OpenSubtitles.com ]=-
Previously on Star Trek:
Strange New Worlds...
UNA: Erica is
critical. but stable.
-[growls]
-[gasps]
BATEL: Still doesn't feel
totally real. I should be dead.
I'm on borrowed time.
I'm not ready to let you go.
-M'BENGA: General Dak-Rah.
-PIKE: I know
you and Chapel
were both stationed
on J'Gal. where
Rah earned his reputation.
[male shouting]
M'Benga. I'm here to provide
healing.
M'BENGA: Get your
hands off me! Don't!
I didn't start the fight.
But I'm glad he's dead.
PIKE: Captain's personal
log. star date 2449.1.
Enterprise has embarked on
a routine scanning mission.
giving Marie and me some time
to enjoy our last
few days together
before her new commission.
I was just getting used
to her decorating choices.
but a captain belongs
on her own ship.
We had every reason to believe
the evasive Gorn tissue
was in full remission.
But. unfortunately.
it's returned.
And it's aggressive.
And yet. hope is not lost.
The Chimera Blossom.
A rare specimen.
long sought-after
for its biological uniqueness.
This flower... it can help her?
M'BENGA: It's a
long shot. Chris.
But it is rumored
to contain a chemical compound
that is universal in its ability
to move invasive molecules
through cell membranes.
Could stop the malignancy.
Buying us time.
Why am I sensing a caveat?
CHAPEL: Well. like
Spock said. it's rare.
And we've tracked
down the one place
the Chimera is
likely to be found.
It's a planet called Kenfori.
-Kenfori?
-That whole system is a no-fly zone.
Yeah. that's true.
But it was once the location
of a Federation
research facility.
focused mainly on
frontier farming.
specifically crop longevity.
The Klingons invaded
at the start of the war
and our claim fell into dispute.
After the war ended. both
sides agreed to give it up.
So it's not just a no-fly
zone. It's the restricted zone.
We can't go anywhere near it
without violating
multiple treaties.
Told them it was crazy. Chris.
I won't allow people to
take risks like this for me.
I won't watch you
die. If this blossom
will help you. we
are going to get it.
But Starfleet will
never authorize this.
This has to be
completely off the books.
That is why we propose
a minimal away team.
Just Dr. M'Benga and myself.
Good plan.
With one adjustment.
Here it comes.
If anyone's going to break the
rules. it's going to be me.
Told them that. too.
I appreciate you
stepping up Mr. Spock.
but if we're caught. the
responsibility falls on me.
You insult me. Captain.
He never gets caught.
I never get caught.
UNA: Lieutenant Scannell.
please pull up cartography
on the buffer zone around
the Kenfori system.
Looks like the treaty line is
on the edge of a
giant dust belt.
Been a long time
since I've flown
into disputed Klingon territory.
Around disputed
Klingon territory.
Enterprise will not
cross that line.
Once the shuttle
clears that dust belt.
personal comms will be down.
We can maintain their cover
by freezing all other
communications as well.
I'm setting up an encrypted
ship-to-ship channel
for the captain to
check in on the hour.
I do not need to remind
you of the consequences
if our away team's
shuttle is discovered.
Ortegas. take us out.
♪
Now comes the fun part.
Show-off.
I'll accept any and all
accolades and applause
and tips.
Admit it. You all
missed my fancy flying.
We did. actually.
Like riding a bike.
With fusion-powered thrusters.
And all this time I thought
you hated my flying.
-You remember Zeta Borealis?
-[laughs]
The moment our shuttle landed.
you kicked open those storm
doors and you threw up.
[laughing]
If memory serves. it
was those Vedalan cigars
-we smoked the night before.
-Oh.
Well. those Vedalans knew
how to throw a party.
-let's be honest.
-Oh. definitely
worth the headache. [chuckles]
[alarm chirping] -Oh. there's
an object in our path.
Indeterminate composition.
Can't get a reading
in this dust belt.
During the war this area would
have been teeming with mines.
Federation and Klingon.
Per the treaty. they
should have all been swept.
Maybe they missed one.
PIKE: I'll keep a distance.
Better raise shields.
Turn on comms.
M'BENGA: Setting comms to
common Klingon frequency range.
It's a communications beacon.
Something's coming through.
You ever see that before?
Yes. in the war.
I was once stationed near
a bombed Klingon mine
with radiation danger.
Loosely translated it
means. "Go back or die."
But why leave a
warning beacon here?
It doesn't matter.
Going back is not an option.
PIKE: Space.
The final frontier.
These are the voyages of
the starship Enterprise.
Its five-year mission:
to explore strange new worlds...
...to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
...to boldly go where
no one has gone before.
♪ ♪
♪
No life signs.
So we are all alone down here.
No. Captain. I
mean no life signs.
All flora. no fauna...
In a bio me this rich?
There must be animal
life here somewhere.
Well. at least the
flora's all that matters.
You see that lake
on the way down?
M'BENGA: Ah. perfect
for fly-fishing.
Yeah. if we weren't
always on a mission.
And if there was
something alive to catch.
Fair point.
That must be our
research facility.
M'BENGA: Christine's research
suggests they would have kept
samples of the flower inside.
PIKE: At least we don't have
to scour this whole forest.
So. what do you think of this
whole Korby-Christine thing?
Ah. Chris. do I
have to remind you
I have three ex-wives?
Well. four. technically.
That was an annulment.
But the next one...
Physician heal thyself?
I like to consider myself
a work in progress.
[tricorder chirping]
Life sign?
The opposite.
♪ ♪
War casualty?
No.
You don't see these
wounds in battle.
His rib cage has
been split open.
Not a single phaser burn.
Given the rate of decay.
I'd say he died
after the evacuation.
Killed by some kind
of animal maybe?
-Only...
-Only no life signs.
An animal that's long gone?
Better not risk it.
Phasers.
Auxiliary power's still on.
Barely.
It's a shame what happened here.
The war took everything.
[clattering]
Chimera Blossoms?
Even more beautiful in person.
-Didn't have to look far. huh?
-Wait.
There's a set of
these in your bag.
Look for the ones in full bloom.
But don't touch
them with bare skin.
What exactly are these?
It's just a precaution.
At improper doses. the
medication can be toxic.
Certain organic poisons
have medicinal value.
Doctors have used
them for centuries
to treat heart disease.
malaria...
How long will this give her?
You know the condition
and treatment
of any crew member
is confidential
unless they jeopardize
the rest of the crew.
Not as your captain.
As your friend.
As Marie's...
I need to know.
I-Is there a chance that
she can really be saved?
This is her only chance.
Just yesterday. we
were out of options.
but Spock found one more.
One to hope for.
A fighting chance. Chris.
[sighs]
♪ ♪
Picking up a minor EM flux
moving towards Kenfori.
Coordinates: Section
Eight. mark 15-29-4.
Sensors show it is moving
in an irregular pattern.
That suggests it's a naturally
occurring phenomenon.
Normal for a dust belt.
Copy. Continue to Section Nine.
Commander. I would like to
recommend a secondary scan
of Section Eight. one
that filters out EM rays.
I've got a hunch.
UNA: Better safe than sorry.
Lieutenant Scannell?
Rescanning Section Eight.
Confirming neutrino
emissions behind the flux.
Checking for a warp signature.
-It's a Klingon battle cruiser.
-[scoffs]
In the war they used
to mask their ships
behind bursts of EM radiation.
Good call. Lieutenant.
This doesn't change a thing.
We continue monitoring from here
until we have reason not to.
Commander. it's a
pretty big coincidence
that they choose now to show up.
What if they spotted
the captain's shuttle?
Maybe.
But Klingons aren't famous
for abiding by treaty.
These could just be scavengers.
I hate to assume causation
where there isn't any.
Uhura. any comms chatter?
Negative. sir.
across all channels.
It's quiet as a
library out there.
Let me know if that changes.
For now... we'll sit tight.
♪ ♪
These wounds are consistent with
those Klingon remains outside.
Something was killing
both humans and Klingons?
If you can call it that.
More like devouring.
Come on. We got
what we came for.
Let's go.
[distant screech]
That had to be alive.
Malfunctioning lab equipment.
I'm still not getting
any life signs.
Humor me.
Nothing.
[shuttle whooshing nearby]
PIKE: Our shuttle.
M'BENGA: It's possible
they don't know about us.
They know about us.
♪
♪ ♪
[growls]
PIKE: It's a hunting party.
They're chasing us
like Skral rabbits.
M'BENGA: If we're captured.
they'll want to
make examples of us.
I'm sure the other direction
was equally as bad.
[Klingon shouts in distance]
You know they'll shoot on sight.
Then we shoot first.
On stun.
[Bytha shouts in Klingon]
♪
[shouts]
[Herak speaks Klingon]
[growls softly]
♪
[snarling]
-[rustling]
-[gasps]
[screeching]
[grunting]
[screaming]
[creature screeches]
-Run.
-[screeching]
[groans]
Are you hitting me
with placebo right now?
Your body has acclimated
to the pain inhibitors.
[groaning]
-Nurse Chapel should...
-[screams]
-I'm so sorry.
-[groans]
[exhales]
-[panting]
-Captain Batel.
I understand your
discomfort has increased.
-Spock.
-You think?
Vulcans have an
ancient technique
of regulating pain
through meditation.
With practice. humans
can do it. too.
However. achieving a
level I suspect you need
will take time we do not have.
Nurse Chapel has suggested
I guide you through it
using a form of mind
meld. if you consent.
Pretty much anything.
[panting]
[breathing shakily]
SPOCK: My mind to your mind.
One breath between us.
Whatever you're
doing. keep doing.
Your ego holds the pain.
Let your mind release your ego.
so it may eclipse
your suffering.
[screeching]
♪ ♪
[both screaming]
[screeching]
[Spock screaming]
CHAPEL [echoing]: Spock!
Snap out of it!
[growls]
Let go of her. Spock. It's me.
It's Christine.
[grunts]
I seem to have
temporarily lost control.
You sure did.
Marie. are-are you okay?
[softly]: Yeah.
What happened?
When we joined minds.
I absorbed your pain.
-But I also...
-I saw something.
SPOCK: Yes. as did I.
It felt both a part
of you and not.
Was it Gorn?
Is that even possible?
I am afraid I do
not have the answer
to either question. Captain.
Thank you. Mr. Spock.
-The pain is much better now.
-[comm chimes]
UHURA [over comm]:
Lieutenant Spock.
Commander Chin-Riley
needs all senior officers
in the ready room.
I will be there momentarily.
My apologies. Ensign.
[door whooshes shut]
UNA: We may have a situation.
Our away team failed to check
in at the prescheduled time.
Their transponders
are both active.
but they are not
responding to any hails
from the Enterprise. which means
they're either having
comms trouble or...
something else happened.
Lieutenant.
Does Commander Pelia plan
to grace us with her presence?
She. uh. got
delayed and sent me.
Nice try. I know she
hates these meetings.
Sit.
We need to get within
emergency beaming range
without attracting
any Klingon attention.
I recommend a slow approach.
Flying at low
impulse will keep us
below the noise limit
of debris motion.
Their sensors will not be able
to tell us apart from
the dust particles.
Well. we'd have to move
at a fraction of impulse
and shut down all
nonessential systems.
But if we were invisible.
might be worth it.
By my calculations. we would
reach Kenfori in four hours.
I can live with that.
Ortegas.
Plot a course with Mr. Spock.
Four hours?
Yeah. that won't work for me.
Explain yourself. Lieutenant.
Why are we tiptoeing
around these Klingons?
It's obvious they know about
the captain and Dr. M'Benga.
Our priority should be
getting them out fast.
UNA: And how do you
propose we do that
without violating
a border treaty?
UHURA: Hypothetically.
even if there were a way.
the interference
from the dust belt
makes transporting impossible.
I've thought about
both problems.
We warp into the
planet's thermosphere.
energize. and warp out. simple.
UNA: Warping into a
low planetary orbit.
It's reckless.
Have you ever done that?
No.
But I could.
Such a dangerous maneuver
is rarely attempted.
I could see the upper
atmosphere maybe.
But if we scrape the
bottom of the thermosphere.
our hull would be
shredded cabbage.
I won't let that happen.
Also. the residual warp
field prohibits transport.
Well. in theory. one
could lock in on a signal
through the residual field.
Well. I don't mean to
step on Mr. Spock's toes.
of course. uh. but you just have
to calibrate the phase inducers
to the warp distortion.
Only. like. really fast.
[chuckles] Yeah.
So my plan checks
off all the boxes.
Uhura. is there any evidence the
Klingons know about our people?
Total comms silence out
there. not even a whisper.
Then Spock's plan
makes the most sense.
You have your orders.
[door whooshes open]
Thanks a lot. Nyota.
[sighs]
Are we gonna discuss
Lieutenant Ortegas?
-[door whooshes shut]
-She was just doing her job.
I needed alternatives.
Your call. but. I mean.
that wasn't like her.
She can be rude at times
but not insubordinate.
Could it be she's back
on rotation too soon?
She passed her psych eval. And
after all she went through.
I'm not surprised if she's a
little rough around the edges.
You get that. La'An.
[door whooshes open]
[door whooshes shut]
[door closes]
PIKE: Not one of those things
showed up on our sensors.
But they looked
very alive to me.
At least. you know.
n-not... dead?
Whatever they are.
they don't register
as life signs anymore.
We are the only
things moving in here.
This is as good a place
as any to hole up. Look.
If Una's following protocol.
the Enterprise is
already on its way.
We need to find comms.
clone the Enterprise's
encrypted channel.
and then coordinate
a rendezvous.
M'BENGA: The comms array.
It's on the roof.
No. we'd have to engage
with those... [sighs]
For serious lack of a
better word. zombies?
Don't call them that.
They were once
Federation scientists.
And Klingons.
Look. I'd really like to
find out what happened here.
Can you recall the lab's data?
The crops that Chapel mentioned.
They used an agent from
the Chimera Blossom
to modify them with genes
from a perennial moss.
A moss that could live
and grow anywhere.
It lays dormant but never dies.
A hybrid supercrop.
Wow. That would feed a lot
of Federation colonists.
Only things went to hell
when the Klingons invaded.
They attacked.
With no regard for
safety protocols.
And everyone in the
facility was exposed.
It inserted moss genomes
into their bodies.
This moss consumes every plant
around it... to proliferate.
And now that is
what they're doing.
Devouring anything
that breathes.
That sounds like the "Z" word.
Wait. we're breathing
that same air.
The agent would have
broken down long ago.
Now I see why you
were so careful
about that Chimera Blossom.
Don't overthink it.
Joseph...
why would Marie need
bio me engineering?
Hybridization?
Spock and I know how
to use it safely.
All right. Answer the question.
You're gonna hybridize
her with what?
-Chris. I cannot...
-Wait. wait. wait. wait. wait.
The Gorn?
That's your miracle treatment?
You're g-going to turn
Marie into a-a what?
A human-Gorn hybrid?
-It is not that rudimentary.
-Then explain it to me.
I already told you. it is
her only chance of survival.
[glass shatters]
Let me understand.
Instead of ridding her
body of the Gorn DNA.
you're gonna make it permanent?
You're going to change her?
Tell me!
Joseph...
Just... what are you
going to do to her?
It was her decision. Chris.
She chose this.
She didn't want you to tell me.
That's why you and
Spock wanted to go...
So I would never know. Oh. my...
This is the only
way to save her.
And that is what we all want.
This is your idea of saving...
Wh-What we all want? No.
Look again. Try harder. I...
There's got to be another way.
She has a few days.
Maybe less.
A few days?
She didn't want me to know
and she didn't want to tell me.
Why?
[snarling]
We're gonna get swarmed.
Overload the charging coil.
[snarling]
[banging. crashing]
[disruptors blasting]
You will come with us.
Thank you. Uh. who are you?
The one holding a disruptor.
[creatures screeching]
[pained grunt]
Ahead of me!
One wrong step and you both die.
Okay.
At least you're not
trying to eat us.
[wind howling]
BYTHA: Forward.
[engines whirring down]
[screeches]
[moaning. wheezing]
Thanks for waking them up.
[approaching footsteps]
[screeches]
[M'Benga grunting]
There are too many!
PIKE: Those are
force field emitters.
M'BENGA: The
console's dead center!
[moaning. wheezing]
Joseph?!
[yells]
[snarling]
We could try luring them
away from your shuttle.
and then lowering the
field. but we need weapons.
-[blade slices]
-[grunts]
M'BENGA: Chris!
I walked right into that one.
Who are you?
First. we talk about you.
I have to say. when your
shuttle crossed the treaty line.
I couldn't believe it.
I thought my viridium
tracker was broken.
You were tracking him?
When a R'ongovian
offers you a drink.
never eat the olives.
Now you found me. Why?
Do you not see a reflection?
The gaze of an old enemy?
I have killed too many Klingons
to know which house you're from.
I am Bytha.
Daughter of Dak'Rah.
champion of House Rah'Ul.
Ambassador Rah's daughter.
BYTHA: Joseph M'Benga...
I am here to make you answer
for the Klingon
you assassinated.
We are now entering the
buffer zone around Kenfori.
It's a ritual.
Lieutenant. keep the ship
at one-seventh impulse.
and not a tick over.
Anything above that will
give away our position.
Aye. Commander.
Maintaining speed.
Bridge to Engineering.
Power down all
non-essential systems.
[power whirring down]
Approaching the battle
cruiser at 200 kilometers.
I have a visual.
-[rumbling]
-[alarm sounds]
Sorry. It's hard to
maneuver at snail speed.
Battle Cruiser at
100 kilometers.
♪ ♪
We are clear of
the Klingon ship.
Comms?
Not picking up any chatter.
Shields?
Still down. They can't see us.
[sighs]
Detecting frozen
volatiles forming.
Recommend reducing speed
to one-eighth impulse.
Amending estimated
arrival to six hours.
We'll have to trust that Pike
and M'Benga are capable enough
to hold down their own
a little while longer.
Lieutenant. one-eighth impulse.
Slowing to one-eighth.
Commander. I'm picking
up something now.
It's a monitoring frequency.
Their sensors are activating.
They're turning their
array toward our ship.
Commander. I think
we've been spotted.
It's fine. I'll survive.
BYTHA: Enough. Leave him.
Your grievance is with
me. Spare my friend.
BYTHA: You are wrong.
My grievance has always
been with my father.
traitor to the empire.
You're not here to avenge him?
He was a war criminal
and a lapdog to the Federation.
I welcomed his death.
A Klingon blood feud.
BYTHA: Dak'Rah brought
shame to our family name.
For his sins.
our house has been subject
to discommendation.
We are shunned. our
bloodline spat upon.
I had to grovel just
to charter a ship here.
There was one way
to restore our name.
Assassinate my father.
Only. you got to him first.
-[grunts]
-[clinking]
Okay. [grunts]
We need to stay calm.
She thinks killing me
will somehow restore her honor.
Our name remains soiled unless
I kill my father's assassin.
Ritual combat?
To the death?
PIKE: He didn't
assassinate Rah.
He acted in self-defense.
Does this human speak the truth?
Are your warrior
days behind you?
I will only ask you once.
Did you assassinate my father?
Their scanners are all over us.
-Uhura.
-Still nothing.
-The Klingons aren't responding.
-Keep trying.
Inform them that we are
here on a rescue mission.
We are not attempting to land.
They haven't raised shields yet.
but I recommend raising ours
while we have the chance.
No. that sends
the wrong message.
Why do we care what they think?
This is pointless. If they...
Finish your thought. Lieutenant.
I just think we're past
the point of diplomacy.
And you thought it wise to
express that concern to me
in the middle of
executing orders?
The Klingons are raising
shields and closing in.
Commander. time to engage.
Evasive maneuvers.
Ortegas. you're up.
Gladly.
-♪
-[trilling accelerating]
Just tell her the truth.
I assassinated Rah.
-Joseph...
-I could have stopped it.
But a mass murderer gave me
the opportunity to kill him.
And I did.
Willingly.
I would do it again.
So yes.
His blood is on my hands.
Was that dishonorable?
I don't know.
But there was justice.
I lied to protect
the monster that
still lives inside me.
Should the day come
when he is needed again.
[grunts]
[groans]
Pick up the blade.
And face me.
PIKE: Joseph.
Don't do this.
M'BENGA: There is a med
kit for you in my bag.
Find your way off
this forsaken planet.
and get the flower to Batel.
Chapel and Spock
have my lab notes.
-There has to be another way.
-BYTHA: Enough!
It is time for one of us to die.
I am ready to face my destiny.
Are you?
This holds the
blood of my father.
It binds us.
Until it is stained with
the blood of the vanquished.
♪
[shouting]
[grunting]
[blade clatters]
[shouts]
[yells]
No!
You cannot forfeit!
Too late.
I do not need the monster today.
By sparing my life.
you damn me to a fate
worse than death.
That field's about to come down.
[snarling]
[growling]
UNA: Lieutenant
Scannell. time?
SCANNELL: Thermospheric
entry in four seconds.
Outer gas compression is at 80%.
So basically we're
flying into a brick wall.
Don't think about
it. just hang on.
[alert beeping]
SCOTTY: Transporter to Bridge.
You need to cut
engine power now!
If you don't compensate
for planetary gravity.
we will come apart.
Copy. Lieutenant. You
work on getting us
that transporter signal.
Pelia warned you
not to volunteer.
And now you actually have
to do what you promised.
[grunting]
The field is back up. but
it won't hold much longer!
[growling]
[blade slices]
You got one.
You're keeping score?
PIKE: Listen. uh...
we work together. we
all get out alive.
[cracking]
♪
She's drawing their attention.
Why?
By sacrificing herself.
she chooses an honorable death.
But no one will ever know.
She will know.
I will know.
May Sto-vo-kor welcome you.
Come on. let's get
to the shuttle.
Alert from Engineering!
Artificial gravity is failing
and inertial
dampeners are at 20%.
If we don't get it back up...
[rumbling]
Ortegas. can you stabilize us?
In a minute.
SCOTTY: Transport to Bridge.
It's a little hard to
maintain pattern integrity
in orbital collapse.
Can you maybe give me a
smidge less turbulence?
UNA: Mr. Scott. any ideas
on how to re-stabilize?
Try firing impulse thrusters
in an alternating pattern.
Auxiliary first. then the main.
I'm gonna energize.
I really hope I don't scramble
the captain and Dr. M'Benga up.
-[growling]
-[Bytha shouting]
[shouting]
[snarling continues]
[Bytha crying out]
SCOTTY: Transport to Bridge. we have
the captain and doctor on board.
Good one. Scotty. We're
maintaining orbit now.
Commander. I'm getting
interference on our comms.
Something's jamming us.
It's not from the dust belt.
Aft view screen.
They're on an attack course.
-Ortegas?
-Already on it.
Say hi to our dust.
Congratulations. everyone.
Erica... stellar flying.
But never do that again.
PIKE: Captain's personal
log. supplemental.
We have returned
from our away mission
with a single Chimera Blossom.
Once Spock synthesizes
its chemical compounds.
Marie's new therapy can begin.
I wonder what effects
this radical treatment
will have on her.
Are you going to turn me in?
Are you worried I will?
That depends on who I'm
talking to right now.
My friend...
or my captain?
Look. I understand
why you didn't tell me
certain things. huh?
I just wish I had known
some of them sooner.
Officially. there was
no mission to Kenfori.
So. nothing happened there.
I don't have any report to file.
But if you did.
hypothetically.
what would it say?
That I had a knife to my
throat and you told a story
to save my life.
That's what happened.
wouldn't you agree?
I would.
You're not a monster. Joseph.
Just a man.
And my friend.
What's up? You wanted to chat?
Have a seat. Lieutenant.
Oh. this feels. uh. official.
At precisely 0240 hours.
you pushed the engines to
one-sixth impulse power.
when I gave you strict orders
to keep us at one-eighth.
I was trying to
dodge tiny asteroids.
We were all on edge.
My finger might have
slipped a little.
A reasonable error
by the standards
I hold most helm officers to.
But you're not
most helm officers.
You don't make
mistakes like that.
Unless they're intentional.
You forced my hand.
You flew just fast enough for us
to be spotted by the Klingons.
so I'd have no choice but
to switch over to your plan.
Look me in the eye
and tell me I'm wrong.
You were going to leave Pike and
M'Benga stranded for six hours.
We all know the Klingons
don't take prisoners.
Disagree with me all you want.
It's not your call to make.
Do you know what could
happen in six hours?
I'm sorry about what
happened to you. Erica.
But I can't have it
affect your judgment.
It was a mistake.
I can get a handle on it.
You better.
Pike and M'Benga were about
to escape in a shuttle.
So your maneuver endangered
everyone on the
ship unnecessarily.
I never meant to do that.
I know.
But there are consequences
for insubordination.
I'm pulling you from
the duty roster.
Two weeks. In that time.
you'll have to report
to the warrant officer for
Chain-of-Command training.
Am I dismissed. sir?
Erica.
Yes. sir?
This can't ever happen again.
You do realize that. right?
I do.
And I'm sorry.
[Ortegas exhales]
♪
Hey.
How's your leg? I
heard you got hurt.
It's fine.
I want to know why
everyone else on the ship
seems to know but me.
Do you have any idea
what could happen?
When that plant fuses
you with the species
that nearly killed you already?
I know all the risks and...
I don't care.
-Fine. you lied to me.
-I never lied to you.
-Then why didn't you tell me?
-Because of you.
Because of this. because I
don't have the space to worry
about how my dying
hurts your feelings.
[exhales]
Chris?
You had days and...
you made what I can only imagine
is the hardest
decision of your life.
-But I wasn't a part of it.
-Yeah. because it wasn't about you.
I just wish I'd have had the
opportunity to be able to say
all the right things. to tell
you I'd be there no matter what.
-No matter what choice you made.
-And that would've been nicer.
But you know what. we
both know you and we know
that you would have demanded
we find another way.
And there is no other way.
I'm scared. Chris.
Hey. come here. come
here. come here.
I know. I know.
I'm scared. too.
♪ ♪
Captioning sponsored by CBS
Captioned by Media Access
Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm